# **Austin Yarborough**

### **Full-Stack Developer**

in LinkedIn

Portfolio

**(**601)-549-3301

austin\_yarborough@yahoo.com

Github

Belton,TX

#### **SUMMARY**

1.5 + years experience in Full-Stack development, high utilization of JavaScript for back and front-end programming. High proficiency in React, HTML, CSS, RESTful APIs, Node.js, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like BootStrap. High success rate when designing and producing full-stack applications.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Angular
- Backend: NodeJS, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, MySQL, APIs
- Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, AWS, CSS3, TypeScript, Microsoft Azure

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Restaurant Reservation Application | Link

- · Produced a React application to allow users to make reservations and use these 3 features searching, editing, and seating.
- · Assembled the functionality that allows users to search, edit, and delete reservations from restaurants with JS functions and DOM.
- Developed with JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js, and CSS for seamless application.

#### ThinkfulBNB | Link

- Constructed the design layout for an application that allows users to book rentals.
- Prioritized with a mobile-first approach through the use of media queries and Flexbot.
- Executed with JS, HTML5, CSS, and Node for the home page.

#### GrubDash | Link

- Built an application that allows users to order food for delivery similar to DoorDash.
- Implemented a React router and Express to build a RESTful API, for HTTP requests for all the reservation data stored in the PostgreSQL database.
- Utilized React, Node.js, Express, Knex, and PostgreSQL to create the application

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Web Developer Program 08/2023 - 02/2024

Online ThinkFul(Chegg)

- · Learned software development industry best practices and standards in a full-time, five-month program.
- Completed several modules and assessments while learning new languages and frameworks, and under the guidance of a senior software engineer in a mentor-student relationship.
- · Accomplished several hands-on role-based and scenario-based projects and virtual labs designed to simulate real-world tasks and challenges.

11/2020 - 05/2021 Line Cook

Temple, TX **Fuzzy's Taco Shop** 

- Enhanced attention to detail when it came to customers' needs, also kept a well-clean and organized workspace.
- Performed with over 100 customers a day to give them an amazing experience.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Certificate, Software Engineering**

08/2023 - 02/2024

Online Thinkful

- Acquired comprehensive knowledge of industry best practices and software development standards, focusing on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- · Demonstrated growth by successfully developing and launching mobile-first applications, actively engaging with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship to expand language proficiency and framework expertise.

05/2022 **A.S Computer Science** 

**Central Texas College** Killeen, TX